MADELINE WENTWORTH

Reliable licensed dental hygiene professional with 6+ years of experience in innovative, modern dental practice. Expertise working with diverse populations, including adolescents, medically compromised, and geriatrics. Experience in soft tissue management, whitening procedures, periodontal charting, sonic and ultrasonic instrumentation. Certified in Basic Life Support and Nitrous Oxide Monitoring. Able to work independently and collaboratively with dentist and office staff and provide mentoring and training to new staff members.

Competent in dental laboratory skills and familiar with electronic health recording systems.

342 Walnut Street, Bismarck, ND58503 yo u remai I @exa m p I e.com (289) 384-2944

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DENTAL HYGIENIST

Bismarck Dental Services, Bismarck, ND May 2014— Present

- · Review patients' health and oral health history prior to dental hygiene procedures
- · Manage patient anxiety using pleasant demeanor, education, and empathy
- Examine patients' teeth, removing plaque and calculus, performing debridement and root planing as needed
- · Operate digital X-ray machine to provide intraoral radiographs
- ♦ Counsel patients on the importance of proper oral hygiene
- · Introduced innovative cleaning approach to reduce patient discomfort and anxiety

DIGITAL ORTHODONTIC LAB TECH

ACME Orthodontics, Lincoln, ND January 2011 — April 2013

- Prepared digital models for 3D printing
- Scanned existing plaster models into digital files
- Prepared modelsand aligners for moving teeth
- Cleaned and prepped printed models for appliance fabrication
- Operated lab equipment
- Followed lab operations policies and procedures

EDUCATION

DENTAL HYGIENE PROGRAM

North Dakota State College of Science, Wahpeton, ND September 2011 — May 2013

KEY SKILLS

- Provide diagnostic, preventive, therapeutic, and minimally invasive restorative services
- Hei p patients deve lop a nd ma i n ta i n good oral health
- Educate patients on the relationship between diet and oral health
- Guide patients'selection of oral care devices
- Document patient care and treatment plans

CERTIFICATIONS

- ♦ Basic Life Support
- ♦ Nitrous Oxide Monitoring